HAJI BAMSI

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

@myportfolio | @mygithub | @linkedin | hibamsi@gmail.com | +255 742 273 111

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A highly resourceful individual with over five years of experience in Software Development on various Information systems initiatives. Passionate about creating thoughts, ideas, and final solutions for technology-enabled small, medium, and enterprise businesses. Willing to explore exciting full-stack development positions for React, Ruby and Rails at both start-ups and legacy businesses. Experience working on a variety of initiatives, including the design and development of a web-based revenue collection system for the local government.

EXPERIENCE

Microverse. Remote

Student | March 2022 - Present

- Mentoring 12 junior web developers through Zoom meetings & slack, providing technical support through code reviews using GitHub.
- Utilizing HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Ruby, and Rails to create at least six projects and more than 20 challenges over the program of ten months.

Ministry of Local Government, Dodoma, Tanzania Systems Developer | August 2015 – July 2019

- Participated as a full-stack developer in the development of the Electronic Medical Record System using AngularJS and Java, which is used by more than a thousand facilities in Tanzania.
- Participated as Full-stack developer in the development of the planning, budgeting, and reporting system (PlanRep) used by 185 local authorities in Tanzania.

EDUCATION

Microverse | March 2022 – Present

Remote Full-stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spending 8 hours a day mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with HTML, CSS, CSS frameworks, JavaScript, React, and Redux, Ruby, Ruby on Rails
- Developing skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

University of Dar es Salaam | Sept 2007 – Nov 2010

B.Sc. in Computer science, Artificial Intelligence

 Computer systems and networks, security, database systems, programming languages, software engineering, and the theory of computing.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, Typescript React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Angular.

Back-End: PHP, Ruby, Rails, MySQL, Postgres

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools.

Product management: UI design | UX Design | Prototyping | Wireframing

Professional: Remote pair-programming, Teamwork, Mentoring.

PROJECTS

Planning and budgeting system used by local governments in Tanzania (Built with Laravel & AngularJS).

Movie Biskop is a movie booking app that allows a user to signup and log in. Add movies or books available from the list. This app was built with react-redux for the front-end, along with rails for the back-end.

"Budget App" Budget app is about building a mobile web application where you can manage your budget: you have a list of transactions associated with a category to see how much money you spent and on what.

The school management system is designed to manage school operations including student Registration, Student Academic Performance, Student Fees, Payment Management, Parent feedback, and Notice Board. (Built with Laravel & AngularJS)